A TRUE WARRIOR
UN VÉRITABLE GUERRIER
Don't get cocky.
Ne sois pas trop sûr de toi.
Who is he?
Qui est-ce ?
He's coming.
Il s'approche.
What are we going to do, Bjorn?
Que va-t-on faire, Bjorn ?
This is bad. Bjorn's gone mad.
Ce n'est pas bon. Bjorn pète les plombs.
Stop him. He'll destroy the ship.
Arrête-le, il va détruire le bateau.
You're crazy.
Tu plaisantes.
How are we supposed to stop a monster like that?
Comment peut-on arrêter un tel monstre ?
Run. No one can stop him now.
Fuyez, personne ne peut l'arrêter.
He's eaten a berserker mushroom.
Il a mangé le champignon qui rend berserker.
All with his bare hands...
Tout ça à main nues...
He's stronger than a monster.
Il est plus fort qu'un monstre.
The Troll of Jom.
Le Troll de Jom.
All right. One more ship.
Bien, encore un bateau.
They're here.
Ils sont là.
-What are we going to do? -Surrender?
- On fait quoi ? - On se rend ?
Damn it. Come on.
Bon sang. Allez.
I'd rather die fighting than be a slave.
Plutôt mourir que de finir esclave.
Listen. Capture the kids alive.
Capturez les jeunes vivants.
If they get hurt, they won't sell for a high price. Be careful.
S'ils sont blessés, on n'en tirera pas un bon prix.
We're going to have some fun with you.
On va bien s'amuser avec vous.
Bjorn?
Bjorn ?
Thors.
Thors.
Listen. You've already lost half of your forces.
Tu as déjà perdu la moitié de tes forces.
Leave now, and I won't take your life.
Abandonne, et je te laisserai la vie.
Be gone, pirates.
Allez-vous-en, pirates.
You cannot defeat me.
Vous ne pouvez pas me vaincre.
-That bastard. -Stop.
- Le salaud. - Arrête.
Don't shoot until Askeladd gives the signal.
Ne tire pas avant qu'Askeladd donne le signal.
What are they doing?
Que font-ils ?
We've got the high ground.
On a l'avantage.
What are they stalling for?
Qu'attendent-ils donc ?
What a crazy man.
Quel enragé.
He's not afraid to take on two whole warships alone.
Il n'a pas peur de prendre un ou deux navires tout seul.
Let's fight too.
Battons-nous aussi.
Fool. You amateurs will make things worse.
Idiot. Vous ne ferez qu'empirer les choses.
Their archers are waiting up on the cliff.
Leurs archers attendent sur la falaise.
He's the one who knows how to handle this.
Il sait ce qu'il faut faire.
But...
Mais...
Don't you understand?
Tu ne comprends pas ?
Except for Thors,
À l'exception de Thors,
we're just a bunch of kids and amateurs.
nous ne sommes qu'une bande d'amateurs.
All we can do is let him handle this.
Il faut le laisser faire.
It looks like they're not the type of men to leave when I say so.
Ils ne sont pas du genre à partir parce que je leur demande.
The archers up on the cliff aren't firing yet.
Les archers sur la falaise ne tirent pas encore.
There's 30 men to the front.
Il y a 30 hommes en face.
I know I could kill that many myself.
Je pourrais les tuer.
But our ships are close.
Mais nos bateaux sont proches.
If they all jumped over to our ship, it'd be a free-for-all.
S'ils sautent dans notre bateau, ce sera la mêlée générale.
I'd be fine if I was alone, but...
Seul, je m'en sortirais, mais...
Are you the leader?
C'est toi le chef ?
In the name of Odin, the Almighty,
Au nom d'Odin, le tout-puissant,
I challenge you to a duel.
je te défie en duel.
If you win, you can do whatever you want.
Si tu gagnes, tu feras ce que tu veux.
If I win, you must withdraw at once.
Si je gagne, tu devras te retirer.
If you refuse,
Si tu refuses,
then you're going to lose three times as many men
tu perdras trois fois plus d'hommes,
to capture a mere 12 slaves.
que les 12 esclaves que tu captureras.
Can I ask you something?
J'ai une question.
Why do you think I'm their leader?
Pourquoi crois-tu que je suis le chef ?
I can smell it.
Je le sens.
Impressive.
Impressionnant.
All right. I accept the duel.
D'accord, j'accepte le duel.
I, Askeladd, son of Olaf, swear in the name of Odin.
Moi, Askeladd, fils d'Olaf, je le jure devant Odin.
Stay back near the ship's bow.
Restez près de la proue.
Okay.
D'accord.
I too
Moi aussi,
can smell something about you.
je sens quelque chose sur toi.
You have the same smell as me,
Nous avons le même don,
Troll of Jom.
Troll de Jom.
He knows who I am?
Il sait qui je suis ?
Did Floki do this?
C'est à cause de Floki ?
You're quick. I like smart men.
Tu es futé. J'aime les hommes intelligents.
My father isn't a bad man like you.
Mon père n'est pas un scélérat comme toi.
Hey. Stay back.
Ne t'en mêle pas.
My father is strong. Die, you pirate.
Mon père est fort. Meurs, pirate.
You idiot. You idiot. Your armor looks weird.
Débile. Ton armure craint.
What an energetic boy. Is that your son?
Quelle énergie, ce garçon. C'est ton fils ?
Stop. You fool.
Arrête, idiot.
Askeladd. Do you have a wife and children?
Askeladd. As-tu une femme et des enfants ?
No.
Non.
I see.
Je vois.
Let's begin.
Commençons.
He's closing up the distance carelessly.
Il s'avance imprudemment.
Too shallow.
Une égratignure.
You're amazing.
Tu es impressionnant.
No one can beat Askeladd.
Personne ne peut vaincre Askeladd.
Father.
Père.
He dodged it. My moment of opportunity...
Il a esquivé. Mon opportunité...
A surprise attack won't work on him anymore.
L'effet de surprise ne marchera plus.
Coming all this way was worth it.
Faire tout ce chemin en valait la peine.
He's an incredible man.
C'est un homme incroyable.
Thors...
Thors...
You're strong.
Tu es fort.
Forgive me, Askeladd.
Pardon, Askeladd.
I can't go easy on you.
Je ne peux pas te ménager.
I'm happy to hear that, Thors.
Tu m'en vois ravi, Thors.
What?
Quoi ?
Hey, hey.
Mince.
Amazing. It's a one-sided fight.
C'est un combat inégal.
Askeladd is in trouble.
Askeladd est mal parti.
But he's able to block all his attacks.
Mais il pare toutes ses attaques.
Father. Kill him.
Père, tue-le.
Oh, no.
Oh, non.
He's going after my sword. It won't hold up for long.
Il s'acharne sur mon épée. Elle ne tiendra pas.
That must mean...
Ça veut dire que...
His sword is also...
Son épée est aussi...
This is it.
C'est bon.
Since I know his target,
Puisque je connais sa cible,
I can predict the arc of his sword.
je peux prédire la trajectoire de son épée.
This is it. A wide swing.
C'est le moment. Un grand coup.
I fell for his trap.
Il m'a tendu un piège.
He was waiting for me to get careless, and swing wide.
Il m'a poussé à l'imprudence, avec un coup large.
He was planning to have me snap his sword, all along.
Il voulait que je brise son épée.
Everything went according to his plan.
Tout a marché comme il l'avait prévu.
Unbelievable.
Incroyable.
I can't believe I fell for it.
Dire que j'ai marché.
You did it.
Tu as réussi.
-Thors. You did it. -That was amazing, Father.
- Thors. Tu as réussi. - C'était magnifique, père.
You won.
Tu as gagné.
What's wrong? Kill me.
Qu'y a-t-il ? Tue-moi.
I don't need to.
Ce n'est pas la peine.
Say you surrender. That's enough for me.
Rends-toi. Cela me suffit.
I'm their leader.
Je suis leur chef.
I can't say that in front of my men.
Je ne peux pas me rendre devant eux.
What's wrong? Kill me.
Qu'est-ce que tu as ? Tue-moi.
If you don't kill me,
Si tu ne me tues pas,
this duel will never end.
ce duel ne finira jamais.
Ouch, my head hurts.
Aïe, j'ai mal à la tête.
What? What's going on?
Hein ? Que se passe-t-il ?
Askeladd...
Askeladd...
Defeat?
Vaincu ?
He lost?
Il a perdu ?
Admit it. I won this duel.
Admets-le. J'ai gagné le duel.
Withdraw your troops at once.
Retire tes troupes.
You really are strong, Thors.
Tu es vraiment fort, Thors.
You could lead a whole army.
Tu pourrais diriger une armée entière.
But why?
Alors, pourquoi ?
Why did you stay in Iceland for 15 years, even though you're such a strong warrior?
Pourquoi es-tu resté 15 ans en Islande, alors que tu es un tel guerrier ?
Don't you think you're wasting your skills?
N'est-ce pas du gâchis ?
No.
Non.
I must rely on a sword like this,
Je dois compter sur une épée,
because I am not yet a master.
car je ne suis pas un maître.
A true warrior
Un vrai guerrier
doesn't need a sword.
n'a pas besoin d'épée.
Thors, you...
Thors, tu...
Why don't you become our leader?
Prends la tête de notre groupe.
Just kidding. Hey, hey.
Je plaisante. Hé.
Why isn't anyone laughing? I was just joking.
Pourquoi personne ne rit ? Je plaisantais.
What? He was joking?
Quoi ? Il plaisantait ?
This is no time for...
Ce n'est pas le moment
joking around with a straight face.
de faire des plaisanteries.
Don't move.
Ne bougez pas.
I'll cut the kid's head off.
Ou je tranche la tête du gamin.
Let go of your sword.
Lâche ton épée.
Hurry up.
Dépêche-toi.
Askeladd. You bastard.
Askeladd. Ordure.
Father.
Père.
Come on. You're such a good man.
Allez. Tu es si bienveillant.
Did you think we were going to follow the rules of the duel?
Tu croyais qu'on allait respecter les règles ?
I was just playing around with you.
Je te faisais marcher.
I wanted to find out how good the famous Troll of Jom really was.
Je voulais mesurer la vraie valeur de Troll de Jom.
I had a good time.
Je me suis bien amusé.
Askeladd.
Askeladd.
You broke the rules of the duel.
Tu as enfreint les règles du duel.
I won this match.
J'ai gagné.
Who cares?
Quelle importance ?
I'm after your head.
Ce que je veux, c'est ta tête.
I know.
Je sais.
I accept.
J'accepte.
The winner of this duel...
Le gagnant de ce duel...
is you.
c'est toi.
Father!
Père !
Father...
Père...
Askeladd.
Askeladd.
I won this duel.
J'ai gagné ce duel.
Keep the promise you made as a warrior.
Tiens la promesse que tu as faite.
I know.
Oui.
In the name of my ancestor Artorius,
Au nom de mon ancêtre Artorius,
I shall withdraw my troops at once.
je retire mes troupes.
Leif. I have a favor to ask you.
Leif. J'ai une faveur à te demander.
Bring my head to Sigvaldi,
Apporte ma tête à Sigvaldi,
the leader of the Jomsvikings.
le chef des Jomsvikings.
If he suspects that I disappeared to avoid his summons,
S'il croit que j'ai disparu pour me soustraire à son injonction,
he'll take his revenge by punishing the village.
il se vengera sur le village.
You're a crazy man.
Tu es fou.
You bastard.
Ordure.
I'll give you my life. Just like you wanted.
Je te donne ma vie. Comme tu le voulais.
Let that child go right now.
Laisse cet enfant, maintenant.
Father. Father.
Père. Père.
I'm glad.
Je suis heureux.
For now...
À cet instant...
Damn kid.
Satané gamin.
You should start valuing your life.
Tu devrais faire plus cas de ta vie.
You should be grateful to Thors.
Tu devrais être reconnaissant à Thors.
He was a man who was worth more than a hundred bratty kids like you.
Il valait plus de 100 morveux comme toi.
Father died.
Père est mort.
Father was so strong.
Père était si fort.
Why did he let go of his sword?
Pourquoi a-t-il jeté son épée ?
How could he say a warrior doesn't need a sword?
Et dit qu'un guerrier n'a pas besoin d'épée ?
That can't be true.
Ce ne peut pas être vrai.
Why...?
Pourquoi...
Why did Father...?
Pourquoi père...
Damn.
C'est injuste.
He...
Il...
He lost to Father.
Il avait perdu contre père.
Damn it.
C'est injuste.
Why was my father the one who died?
Pourquoi c'est père qui est mort ?
Why is he the one who's still alive?
Pourquoi est-il celui qui est en vie ?
Damn it.
C'est injuste.
Damn it all.
Bon sang !
I'm surprised they abandoned these nice ships.
Pourquoi abandonner ces beaux bateaux ?
It must have been a big decision.
Cela a dû leur coûter.
They can't move the ship without Thors.
Ils ne peuvent pas naviguer sans Thors.
Thors could row as hard as five men.
À lui seul, il ramait comme cinq hommes.
Really?
Ah, oui ?
Things worked out well.
Tout a bien tourné.
I was wanting to get a third ship.
Je voulais un troisième navire.
Twenty-eight men injured.
Vingt-huit blessés.
How many died?
Et de morts ?
None? Not even one? Impossible.
Aucun ? Pas un ? Impossible.
Askeladd.
Askeladd.
Hey.
Hé.
Come to the stern. Askeladd.
Viens à l'arrière. Askeladd.
What do you want? Shut up already.
Que veux-tu ? Tu ne peux pas te taire ?
It's Thors' kid.
C'est le fils de Thors.
He was hiding inside the ship.
Il était caché dans le navire.
Look at him. The kid's got a dagger.
Regarde. Il a une dague.
He's going to kill us.
Il va nous tuer.
Oh, no. I'm so scared.
Oh, non. Je meurs de peur.
How dare you...?
Comment as-tu osé...
How dare you kill Father?
Comment as-tu osé tuer mon père ?
I'm going to kill you.
Je vais te tuer.
I'm going to kill you, no matter what.
Je te tuerai, quoi qu'il m'en coûte.
I'm going to kill you!
Je te tuerai !
He's just a kid.
C'est un gamin.
But that look in his eyes...
Mais ce regard...
What do you want to do, Askeladd?
Que veux-tu faire, Askeladd ?
Shall we throw him overboard?
On le jette à la mer ?
Leave him.
Laissez-le.
He will die soon anyway.
Il mourra de toute façon.
Father...
Père...